José Juan Isaac Taveras López

(667)-225-7335/josejuanisaac@gmail.com

PO BOX 2096 Vega Baja, Puerto Rico 00694

Software engineer with +10 years of experience in database design & maintenance, data analytics & visualizations, full stack web development, and network security analysis. Proven ability to conduct localized research to produce reports that directly drive organization goals and improve operational processes.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Assistant Manager, 03/2022-08/2022

Dominos' Pizza Inc, Winchester, Virginia

Ensured operational excellence by performing managerial tasks, such as scheduling, maintaining inventory and/or evaluating employee performance. Manage and supervise each store section: makeline, driver dispatch and backend office. Opened and closed store on a weekly basis, ensuring cash till are correct and deposits are completed. Provided customer support, conducted new employee training, smoothed out issues between employees, liaise between employees and upper management.

Target Digital Network Analyst, 03/2019-12/2021

U.S. Army, Fort Meade, Maryland

Conducted target development such as open-source research and signals analysis. Authored and contributed to publishing several reports used by federal organizations. Maintained and organized documentation of collected data for presentations. Used network analysis tools to produce pattern-of-life visualizations. Collaborated in a joint military environment by developing knowledge management and project communication strategies to overcome workspace restrictions imposed by COVID-19. Developed browser-based tools to visualize and edit structured data sets (JSON, CSV).

Business Intelligence Developer, 08/2014-03/2017

Wovenware, San Juan, Puerto Rico

Operated as a consultant and performed duties at client job site. Produced descriptive analytics to display aggregate user information using Qlikview BI software. Designed query scripts while verifying the analysis matched expected results. Performed maintenance and supervised correct Qlikview backend server operation.

Web Developer, 06/2010-09/2015

Rubric Solution, Manati, Puerto Rico

6-month recurring project-based work. Designed initial SQL ER diagram and implementation using MySQL. Integrated Open-Source chat software into underlying system and built custom group management interface. Implemented payment process flow with local banking provider that used XML SOAP for secure information transfer.

EDUCATION

University of Puerto Rico, Mayagüez Campus

Bachelor of Science in Computer Engineering (2014)

SKILLS

- Front-end: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Qlikview Dashboards, Excel
- Back-end: PHP, Ruby, Qlikview Script, MySQL
- · Frameworks: Ruby on Rails, WAMP
- Languages: Native Spanish, full English, conversational French and Italian.

TRAINING AND CERTIFICATIONS

- U.S. ARMY Fully Qualified as Basic Target Digital Network Analyst, Fort Meade, MD (2020)
- Army Analysis and Reporting Course, Goodfellow AFB, San Angelo, TX (2018)
- Web Development Bootcamp, DevBootcamp, San Francisco, CA (2016)